export const chapter = "Chapter - 21: Industry: Types and Factors ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What major factor does the text attribute to the improvement in the quality of life for people, including those with limited resources?",
        optionA: "Education",
        optionB: "Healthcare",
        optionC: "Industry",
        correctAnswer: "C) Industry",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the past, why did the Mughal ruler Aurangzeb have to stay in South India for the latter part of his rule?",
        optionA: "To enjoy the pleasant climate",
        optionB: "To avoid political conflicts",
        optionC: "Due to the slow pace of travel",
        correctAnswer: "C) Due to the slow pace of travel",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What major historical event is credited with changing the face of the world in the 18th century, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "The French Revolution",
        optionB: "The Industrial Revolution",
        optionC: "The Renaissance",
        correctAnswer: "B) The Industrial Revolution",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary role of an industry, according to the text?",
        optionA: "To provide entertainment services",
        optionB: "To create economic prosperity",
        optionC: "To manufacture products from raw materials",
        correctAnswer: "C) To manufacture products from raw materials",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What significant development marked the beginning of the Industrial Revolution?",
        optionA: "The invention of the automobile",
        optionB: "The invention of the steam engine",
        optionC: "The discovery of electricity",
        correctAnswer: "B) The invention of the steam engine",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the impact of machine-produced goods being cheaper than hand-crafted goods on traditional craftsmen?",
        optionA: "They prospered and thrived",
        optionB: "They suffered and went out of business",
        optionC: "They adapted to the new technologies",
        correctAnswer: "B) They suffered and went out of business",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following is NOT mentioned as a source of raw materials for industries in the text?",
        optionA: "Minerals",
        optionB: "Marine Products",
        optionC: "Precious Metals",
        correctAnswer: "C) Precious Metals",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following is an example of a primary industry according to the text?",
        optionA: "Cement industry",
        optionB: "Toy industry",
        optionC: "Entertainment industry",
        correctAnswer: "A) Cement industry",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In terms of ownership, what type of industry is owned and managed by a private individual or group of individuals?",
        optionA: "Public Sector Industries",
        optionB: "Private Sector Industries",
        optionC: "Cooperative Sector Industries",
        correctAnswer: "B) Private Sector Industries",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What kind of industry is typically associated with small-scale production, a one-time investment in machinery, and a large workforce?",
        optionA: "Cottage Industries",
        optionB: "Large-scale Industries",
        optionC: "Small-scale Industries",
        correctAnswer: "C) Small-scale Industries",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Industrial Revolution in the __________ century in Europe changed the face of the world.",
        options: ["17th", "18th", "19th"],
        correctAnswer: "18th",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The process of manufacturing was divided into several steps, each of which was dealt by a different __________ and worker.",
        options: ["craftsman", "machine", "supervisor"],
        correctAnswer: "machine",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A large-scale industry operates on a very large scale in terms of investment, range of market, transportation, work force, and energy, such as the __________ industry.",
        options: ["toy", "textile", "iron and steel"],
        correctAnswer: "iron and steel",
      },
      {
        question:
          "An industry requires a regular and assured supply of __________ material, especially a large scale industry using heavy and bulky raw material.",
        options: ["finished", "raw", "processed"],
        correctAnswer: "raw",
      },
      {
        question:
          "An industry cannot be set up at any place you feel like; several favourable factors have to be looked at before an industry is set up at a place or in a particular __________.",
        options: ["region", "sector", "product"],
        correctAnswer: "region",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In terms of ownership, industries can be classified into several types, one of which is the __________ industry, such as Tata Motors Ltd, Godrej Group, and Reliance Industries.",
        options: ["public sector", "private sector", "joint sector"],
        correctAnswer: "private sector",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A cottage industry is a small industry, chiefly run by a few people, like the members of a family; it produces goods at a very small scale, and it procures raw materials from local sources and supplies the finished goods in the local market. Normally, it does not involve much __________ and many modern machines.",
        options: ["of specialization", "division of labor", "technology"],
        correctAnswer: "of specialization",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The means of transport is an important factor if the raw materials or finished goods are bulky and heavy. A place well connected by efficient roadways, railways, waterways, and airways is preferred for setting up an __________.",
        options: ["industry", "enterprise", "agricultural farm"],
        correctAnswer: "industry",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A developed country is called so because it has attained a high degree of industrial development, which also brings economic development and __________.",
        options: ["recession", "depression", "prosperity"],
        correctAnswer: "prosperity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What kind of industry is typically associated with small-scale production, a one-time investment in machinery, and a large workforce?",
        options: [
          "cottage industries",
          "large-scale industries",
          "small-scale industries",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "small-scale industries",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Agriculture is directly related to food security.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question: "The world population is growing at about 1.1% per year.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "With the growing population, agricultural land is expanding.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Modern ways of living have led to a reduction in food wastage.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The use of chemical fertilizers and pesticides has a positive impact on soil fertility.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Industrial Revolution in the 18th and early 19th centuries had no significant impact on agriculture.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question: "India is traditionally an industrial country.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government introduced land reforms to redistribute land among landless laborers.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Indian farmers primarily use organic fertilizers in their farming practices.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government has not taken any steps to address the problems associated with agriculture.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "B",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
